Prathmesh Kamble

Ramnagar, Road No 28, Wagle Estate, Github: https://github.com/Pratham41
Thane(W), Thane – 400604

LinkedIn: prathmesh-kamble-61a904212

Email : <u>kambleprathmesh41@amail.com</u>

Mobile No: +91 8433635318

SUMMARY

An ingenious Software Engineer with 1 year of experience in full stack development. Highly Organized, self-motivated and proficient with various programming languages. Seeking to learn more tech stack and increase my knowledge to build scalable full stack architectures.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

• **B.E (Computer Engineering)** : 2017 to 2020.

• **Diploma (Computer Engineering)** : 2014 to 2017.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

• Digital Trons LLP | Atlanta, USA.

Full Stack Developer | March 2022 - June 2022.

Developed Front-end architectures using React.js, HTML, Bootstrap and SCSS.

Developed Back-end architectures and GraphQL API using various backend technologies like Node.js, Express.js, Knex.js, Serverless using various databases like PostgreSql.

Writing clean, functional code for front-end and back-end. Testing and fixing bugs and other coding issues. Create and execute unit tests and perform basic application testing.

Oriserve | No.15 3 Block F, 112 T, B Jagpat Marg, Jacob Circle, Mumbai - 400011.

Software Engineer | November 2021 – February 2022.

Developed Back-end architectures and RESTful API's using various backend technologies like Node.js and Express.js using various databases like MongoDB and MySQL.

Writing clean, functional code for the back-end. Testing and fixing bugs and other coding issues. Create and execute unit tests and perform basic application testing.

SKILLS

Programming Languages : C, Java, Python, JavaScript.

Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, SCSS.

JavaScript Libraries : React.js, Redux, Angular.js

Database : MySql, MongoDB, postgreSql.

Backend Services: Node.js, Express.js, RESTful API, GraphQL, Knex.js.

Operating Systems: Linux, Windows.

Version Control systems: Git, Github, Gitlab, BitBucket.

Certification: Microsoft Technology Associate (MTA).

PROJECTS

Project Name : E-Commerce web application

Technology: React.js, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB.

Description : An E-Commerce web application in which customers can buy

products.

Features : 1. Admin panel to monitor and manage products and orders.

2. PayPal payment gateway.

3. Users can track orders.

• Project Name : **Expense Tracker**

Technology : React.js, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB.

Description : A web application in which user can track their expense and income.

Features : 1. User can view data in tabular as well graphical format.

2. User can apply filters like last week, last month and custom.

CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Participated in Avalon national level project competition in Terna College of Engineering Nerul, New Bombay.

Participated in national level project competition in Universal College of engineering Vasai.

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the information given herewith is correct to my knowledge and I will be responsible for any discrepancy.

Place: Thane (Prathmesh Kamble)